Guide to the First Congregational Church of Portland records 1849-2016
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Members, 1895-2011; Series E
  - Himes, George H., Subseries 3
    - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 58/30, 59/1)
    - Correspondence, 1901-1902 (Box-folder 59/2)
    - Programs for celebration of Himes' 90th birthday, 1934 May 18 (Box-folder 59/3)
      Additional copies of program located in 24/16.
    - Programs for dedication of George H. Himes park, 1935 May 18 (Box-folder 59/4)
  - Hinkle, Charlie S. (Box-folder 59/5)
  - Howard, Oliver O. (Box-folder 59/6-59/7)
  - Howe, Ellie N. and Florence E. (Box-folder 59/8)
  - Hutchinson, Clinton C., Reno, and Alice (Box-folder 59/9)
  - Huntington, Walter M. (Box-folder 59/10)
  - Irwin, Phil (Box-folder 59/11)
  - Jensen, Gertrude Pratt (Box-folder 59/12)
  - Kellogg, Edwin D. and Alice (Box-folder 59/13)
  - Knapp, Jonathan (Box-folder 59/14)
  - Kribs, Mrs. Frederick (Box-folder 59/15)
  - Larimer, Arhur E. (Box-folder 59/16)
  - Liljeholm, Joyce (Box-folder 59/17)
  - Little, Lena (Box-folder 59/18)
  - McKnight family (Box-folder 59/19)
  - McReynolds, William T. (Box-folder 59/20)
  - Moke family (Box-folder 59/21)
  - Morse, Ada Doernbecker (Box-folder 59/22)
  - Murray, Evelyn (Box-folder 59/23-59/24)
  - Pierce, John C. (Box-folder 60/1)
  - Plankinton (Box-folder 60/2)
  - Pollard family (Box-folder 60/3)
  - Raven, Elvira (Box-folder 60/4)
  - Scott, Harvey W. (Box-folder 60/5)
  - Scott, Harvey W. - Address, "Religion: Its Permanent Substance and Transitory Forms", 1895 (Box-folder 60/6)
  - Shindler, Gabriel (Box-folder 60/7)
  - Shull, Martha (Box-folder 60/8)
  - Smith, Mark (Box-folder 60/9)
  - Stanton, John W. (Box-folder 60/10)
  - Steel, James (Box-folder 60/11)
  - Stevens, Beatrice (Box-folder 60/12)
  - Stevenson, Lois (Box-folder 60/13)
  - Taka, Gamil N. (Box-folder 60/14)
  - Tuttle, Harold S. (Box-folder 60/15)
  - Walth, Brent (Box-folder 60/16)
  - Warren family (Box-folder 60/17)
  - Wiley, Alison (Box-folder 60/18)
  - Wyman, Margaret (Box-folder 60/19)
  - Young, Maud Cook (Box-folder 60/20)
  - Zilk, Ruth (Box-folder 60/21)
  - Zumwalt, Abigail (Box-folder 60/22)
  - Minister members, Subseries 4
    Materials on church attendees who were ordained ministers, but who did not preach at First Congregational Church.
    - General materials re minister members (Box-folder 60/23)
    - Bailey, Ruth (Box-folder 60/24)
    - Buttery, John D. (Box-folder 60/25)
    - Harding, Albert H. (Box-folder 60/26)
    - Huenemann, Ruben (Box-folder 60/27)
    - Paulson, Peter (Box-folder 60/28)
    - Ross, Karl Eugene (Box-folder 60/29)
    - Sevetson, Donald J. (Box-folder 60/30)
    - Vaughan, Gary (Box-folder 60/31)
- Senior Ministers, 1849-2014; Series F
  - Biographical sketches of Senior Ministers, 1951; circa 1960; 2000 (Box-folder 60/32)
  - Rosters and notes re Senior Ministers (Box-folder 60/33)
  - Ackerman, Arthur W., Subseries 1
    Served as Senior Minister 1896-1902.
    - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 60/34)
    - Calendar for Central Congregational Church, Torrington, Connecticut, 1903 June (Box-folder 60/35)
    - Correspondence and notes by and about Ackerman, 1898-1902 (Box-folder 60/36)
    - Sermons, writings, etc. (Box-folder 60/37)
    - "How Music Became a Part of Christian Worship", 1900 (Box-folder 60/38)
  - Atkinson, George H., Subseries 2
    Served as Senior Minister 1863-1872.
    - Correspondence and research re Alta Blood's research into Atkinson and his descendants, 1955 (Box-folder 60/39)
    - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 61/1-61/2)
    - Biographical sketches (Box-folder 61/3)
    - Newspaper articles by and about Atkinson (Box-folder 61/4)
    - "In Memoriam. Rev. George H. Atkinson", 1889 (Box-folder 61/5)
      Bound volume including obituary and text of Atkinson's funeral service.
    - Documents and images relating to edifices named for Atkinson (Box-folder 61/6)
      Includes materials on Atkinson Memorial Congregational Church of Oregon City, Oregon, and Atkinson School in Portland, Oregon.
    - Materials re Atkinson's relationship with Pacific University (Box-folder 61/7)
  - Caldwell, Royald V., Subseries 3
    Served as Senior Minister 1960-1971.
    - Research files and clippings re Caldwell and family (Box-folder 61/8)
    - Biographical data and resumes (Box-folder 61/9)
    - Comments on abortion bill, undated (Box-folder 61/10)
    - Materials re Faith United Church of Christ, Chicago, Illinois., 1959-1960 (Box-folder 61/11)
      Church was where Caldwell preached prior to coming to Oregon.
    - Correspondence and records re Caldwell's move to Portland, 1960 (Box-folder 61/12)
    - Installation service program, 1960 May 3 (Box-folder 61/13)
    - Letter of recommendation for Caldwell by A. J. Buttery, 1971 (Box-folder 61/14)
    - Lists of books donated by Caldwell to church, 1969-1970, undated (Box-folder 61/15)
    - Note from Helen Ross to Caldwell, 1969 December 4 (Box-folder 61/16)
    - Observations for the Objectives Committee, 1968 August 22 (Box-folder 61/17)
    - Report to Church and Ministry Committee, 1961 January 24 (Box-folder 61/18)
    - Final report, 1971 February 12 (Box-folder 61/19)
    - Sermons, 1960-1971 (Box-folder 61/20-61/21)
    - Sermon, "Emmaus Road - an Ongoing Call", 1993 April 25 (Box-folder 61/22)
    - Tribute to Caldwell, 1993 (Box-folder 61/23)
  - Clapp, Eaton T. - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 62/1)
    Clapp served as Senior Minister 1886-1894.
  - Clapp, Eaton T. - Handwritten transcript of quotes by Clapp, undated (Box-folder 62/2)
    Transcript written by George H. Himes.
  - Clapp, Eaton T. - Eventide service program for Clapp's last day as Senior Minister, 1894 January 28 (Box-folder 62/3)
  - Chamberlain, Peasley B. - Biographical sketches, etc. (Box-folder 62/4)
    Chamberlain served as Senior Minister 1855-1862.
  - Chamberlain, Peasley B. - Transcript of November 26, 1855 letter from Chamberlain to Reverend M. Badger, circa 2000 (Box-folder 62/5)
  - Clarke, Clement G., Subseries 4
    Served as Senior Minister 1923-1928.
    - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 62/6)
    - Article by Clarke, "The Dear Eternal God", 1930 (Box-folder 62/7)
    - Calendar of Sunday night addresses by Clarke, 1924 (Box-folder 62/8)
    - Correspondence by and about Clarke, 1923-1927 (Box-folder 62/9)
  - Cruzan, John A. (Box-folder 62/10)
    Served as Senior Minister 1877-1881.
  - DeWet, Anton (Box-folder 62/11)
    Served as Senior Minister 2010-2013.
  - Dyott, Luther R. - Research files and clippings. (Box-folder 62/12)
    Dyott served as Senior Minister 1907-1917.
  - Dyott, Luther R. - Resolution re Dyott and reply letter from Adele Y. Dyott, 1917 December (Box-folder 62/13)
  - Dyott, Luther R. - Sermon series calendars, 1912; circa 1915 (Box-folder 62/14)
  - Eaton, James D. (Box-folder 62/15)
    Served as Senior Minister 1873-1876.
  - House, Elwin Lincoln, Subseries 5
    Served as Senior Minister 1902-1906.
    - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 62/16)
    - Correspondence by and about House, 1902-1905 (Box-folder 62/17)
    - Installation service program, 1903 May 7 (Box-folder 62/18)
    - "The Glories of Friendship", 1924 (Box-folder 62/19)
  - Ellick, Michael - brochure about pastoral candidate Michael Ellick., 2014
    Ellick became Senior Minister in 2014.
  - Lyman, Horace, Subseries 6
    Served as Senior Minister 1851-1854.
    Subscription list which Lyman authored is in 113/1.
    - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 62/21)
    - Correspondence - Printouts of letters, 1849-1853 (Box-folder 62/22)
      Microfilmed correspondence which Donald J. Sevetson printed out circa 2000.
    - Correspondence - Printouts of letters, 1852-1854 (Box-folder 62/23)
    - Correspondence - Letter to Josiah Failing, 1855 March 3 (Box-folder 62/24)
      Also includes typescript of letter.
    - Sermon, 1880 October 27 (Box-folder 62/25)
    - Transcripts of autobiographical account made by Lyman, undated (Box-folder 62/26)
    - Handwritten transcript of 1851 notice by Rev. Horace Lyman, done by George Himes, 1903 April 4 (Box-folder 62/27)
  - McElveen, William T., Subseries 7
    Served as Senior Minister 1919-1923.
    - Clippings and articles re McElveen (Box-folder 63/1)
    - Correspondence re McElveen's call and acceptance, 1919 (Box-folder 63/2)
    - Resignation attempt, 1921 December - 1922 January (Box-folder 63/3)
    - Resignation, 1923 (Box-folder 63/4)
    - Sermons, 1919-1923 (Box-folder 63/5)
    - Sermons delivered at Plymouth Congregational Church, St. Paul, Minnesota, undated (Box-folder 63/6)
  - Marvin, Frederic R. (Box-folder 63/7)
    Marvin served as Senior Minister 1882-1885.
  - Marvin, Frederic R. - Sermon, "Consecrated Womanhood", 1883 (Box-folder 63/8)
  - Reed, Lincoln Y., Subseries 8
    Served as Senior Minister 1971-1986.
    - Articles about Reed (Box-folder 63/9)
    - Biographical information and resumes (Box-folder 63/10)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1986 (Box-folder 63/11)
    - Event flyers and invitations, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 63/12)
    - Correspondence, memos, and programs re installation service, 1972 (Box-folder 63/13)
    - Program for Reed's memorial service, 2010 (Box-folder 63/14)
    - Remarks delivered at joint meeting, 1984 February 1 (Box-folder 63/15)
    - Sermons, 1971-1983 (Box-folder 63/16)
  - Rogers, John, Subseries 9
    Served as Senior Minister 1987-1994.
    - Articles about Rogers and family (Box-folder 63/17)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 63/18)
    - Event flyers and programs, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 63/19)
    - Minutes and motion re installation of Rogers as Senior Minister, 1987 April 12 (Box-folder 63/20)
    - Notes on Rogers' career, circa 1987 (Box-folder 63/21)
    - Sermons, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 63/22)
  - Ross, Patricia S., Subseries 10
    Served as Senior Minister 1996-2008.
    Includes some earlier materials from her time as Associate Minister at First Congregational Church.
    - Articles about Ross and family, 1994-2001 (Box-folder 63/23)
    - Biographical sketch (Box-folder 63/24)
    - Correspondence, 1986-2008 (Box-folder 63/25)
    - Event programs, 1989-2008 (Box-folder 63/26)
    - Ministerial profile, 1985 (Box-folder 63/27)
    - "My Sabbatical - A Preliminary Report", 1992 (Box-folder 63/28)
    - Sermons, 1992-2005 (Box-folder 63/29)
  - Wallace, George R. (Box-folder 64/1)
    Served as Senior Minister 1894-1896.
  - Wallace, George R. - Book of newspaper clippings re Wallace, 1894-1896 (Box-folder 64/2)
  - Walker, Raymond B., Subseries 10
    Served as Senior Minister 1929-1959.
    - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 64/3)
    - Articles and clippings (Box-folder 64/4)
    - Address at Pacific University commencement ceremony, 1955 May (Box-folder 64/5)
    - Newsletter re celebration of Walker's 10th anniversary as minister, 1939 (Box-folder 64/6)
    - Celebration tea for Walker's 25th anniversary as minister, 1954 (Box-folder 64/7)
    - Correspondence - Congratulatory letter from Harry L. Meyer, 1929 December 10 (Box-folder 64/8)
    - Correspondence with Alta Blood, 1953 (Box-folder 64/9)
    - Correspondence - Letter of appreciation for sermon from Bruno C. Linde, 1955 January 25 (Box-folder 64/10)
    - Correspondence - Letter re appointment of Walker as Minister Emeritus, 1959 February 17 (Box-folder 64/11)
    - Correspondence - Letter from Walker following wife Ruth Walker's death, 1968 June 15 (Box-folder 64/12)
    - Invitation and program for service of recognition, 1929 September 10 (Box-folder 64/13)
    - Invitation to Young Married People tea at Walker residence, circa 1939 (Box-folder 64/14)
    - Summer newsletters by Walker, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 64/15)
    - Recognition banquet program and ephemera, 1959 June 23 (Box-folder 64/16)
    - Resignation, 1959 (Box-folder 64/17)
    - Sermons, 1934-1961 (Box-folder 64/18-64/19)
    - Travel to Europe, 1953 (Box-folder 64/20)
- Associate Ministers, 1926-2012; Series G
  - List of past and present associate ministers, 1986 (Box-folder 64/21)
  - Bradley, Trudy, Subseries 1
    - Letter recommending Reverend Trudy Bradley for recognition with ministerial partnership standing, 2012 July 21 (Box-folder 64/22)
    - Master thesis, "In the Fullness of Time: A Mother's View of Forgiveness", 2009 (Box-folder 64/23)
    - Notice re of Bradley's death and assistant minister position, 2012 December 4 (Box-folder 64/24)
    - Obituary, 2012 October 7 (Box-folder 64/25)
    - Program for memorial service, 2012 October 27 (Box-folder 64/26)
    - DVD of memorial service, 2012 October 27 (Box-folder 158/2)
      Viewing copy for on-site use only.
    - Sermons, 2011-2012 (Box-folder 64/27)
  - Davis, Paul, 1996-2007 (Box-folder 64/28)
  - Harlow, Charles, circa 1955 (Box-folder 64/29)
  - Hawley, Quinn L., 1963-1969 (Box-folder 65/1)
  - Jasper, F. M., 1926 (Box-folder 65/2)
  - Madsen, David, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 65/3)
  - Olney, Mary, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 65/4)
  - Randlett, John C., 1966 (Box-folder 65/5)
  - Smith, Anne Pearse - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 65/6)
  - Smith, Anne Pearse - Other materials, 1971-1997 (Box-folder 65/7)
    Contains receipts for traveler's insurance payments and Smith's memorial service program.
  - Start, H. A. (Box-folder 65/8)
- In-Care Ministers, 1972-2008; Series H
  Materials relating to people whom the First Congregational Church assisted during their divinity studies.
  - Records, correspondence, and clippings re In-Care Ministers, 1992-2002 (Box-folder 65/9)
  - Gustafson, Mark, 1972 (Box-folder 65/10)
  - Lewitz, Antje, 1991-1992, 2008 (Box-folder 65/11)
    Lewitz was a German who worked on First Congregational Church staff in 1992 to gain experience working in an American metropolitan church.
  - Lloyd, Katie, 1990-1992, undated (Box-folder 65/12)
  - Rinehart-Nelson, Judith, 1987-1997 (Box-folder 65/13)
    Includes poems Rinehart-Nelson wrote, some under the name Judith Denton.
- Interim Ministers, 1958-2013; Series I
  - Bradford, Amory (Box-folder 65/14)
  - Cone, Roger - Clipping, 1995 July 29 (Box-folder 65/15)
  - Dailey, James, Jr., 1961 (Box-folder 65/16)
  - Dick, Raymond Alan, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 65/17)
  - Smith, R'Dean, 1982, 1993 (Box-folder 65/18)
  - Svendsen, Charles, 2013 (Box-folder 65/19)
  - Wingfield, Marshall, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 65/20)
  - Wingfield, Marshall - "Grass on the Mountains and Other Sermons", 1966 (Box-folder 65/21)
- Ordinations and installations, 1954-2013; Series J
  - Programs for installation services held at First Congregational Church, 1954-1982 (Box-folder 65/22)
  - Programs for and clippings re ordinations held at First Congregational Church, 1979-2013 (Box-folder 65/23)
  - Ordination of Mark Gustafson, 1972 (Box-folder 65/24)
  - Ordination of Stephen M. Lusk, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 66/1)
  - Ordination of Catherine J. Tinker, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 66/2)
- Lectures, 1931-2013; Series K
  - Lecture and course schedules, 1931-1968 (Box-folder 66/3)
  - Constitutional lecture series, 2003 (Box-folder 66/4)
  - Forum lectures, Subseries 1
    For administrative records relating to the Forum Committee, see Series B: Groups.
    - Clippings re Forum, 1984-1985; 1987 (Box-folder 66/5)
    - Announcement for forum series, "To Build a City", 1984 August 14 (Box-folder 66/6)
    - Correspondence and memos re Forum, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 66/7)
    - Forum event notices and publicity, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 66/8)
      Does not include press releases.
    - Forum financial records, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 66/9)
    - Sunday/Adult Forum press releases, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 66/10)
    - Forum press releases, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 66/11)
    - Sunday Forum speaker schedule, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 66/12)
    - Summer Forums schedule and attached resolutions, 1991 (Box-folder 66/13)
    - Forum survey questionnaire, 1985 June (Box-folder 66/14)
  - Programs for "Great Decisions" lectures, 1955-1972 (Box-folder 66/15)
  - CD of Nerve gas lecture by Evelyn Murray, 1990 (Box-folder 158/1)
    Listening copy for on-site use only
  - DVD, Nobel Leaureate Forum, F. W. deKlerk - "Preventing War and Ending World Conflicts", 2012 February 29 (Box-folder 158/3)
  - Helen Oliver Memorial Lectures, Subseries 2
    Also called Egbert S. and Helen Oliver Memorial Lectures.
    For administrative records of the Oliver Lectures Committee, see Series B: Groups.
    - Programs, correspondence, etc., 1990-1992 (Box-folder 66/17)
    - Programs, correspondence, etc., 1993-1997 (Box-folder 66/18)
    - Programs, correspondence, etc., 1998-2006 (Box-folder 66/19)
    - Program for lecture, "Ending Homelessness", 2013 November (Box-folder 66/20)
    - "Thomas Condon of Oregon: A Man with a Mission", 1983 (Box-folder 66/21)
      Lecture presented by Egbert S. Oliver.
    - Summation of 1986 lectures, 1986 October (Box-folder 66/22)
  - Lecture series, "Revolution and Rebirth", 1982
- Music, 1895-2005; Series L
  For Music Committee administrative records, see Series B: Groups.
  - Advent Brown Bag concerts, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 66/24)
  - Annual Spring Concert programs, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 66/25)
  - "Broadway a la Carte", 1985 (Box-folder 66/26)
  - Brochure for church music program, circa 1990 (Box-folder 66/27)
  - Chancel Choir concert programs, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 66/28)
  - Church choir, Subseries 1
    - Letter from "Lenora" to Alta Blood re choir history, 1955 June 26 (Box-folder 66/29)
    - Notes on history of first choir, circa 1951 (Box-folder 66/30)
    - Clippings re choir and choir members, circa 1944; 1989; 2005 (Box-folder 66/31)
    - Attendance record, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 66/32)
    - Correspondence re choir, 1954-1974 (Box-folder 67/1)
    - Correspondence - Letters of appreciation, 1981, 1986 (Box-folder 67/2)
    - Correspondence - Thank-you notes, 1988 (Box-folder 67/3)
    - Correspondence - Letters and memos to choir, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 67/4)
    - Programs for Youth and Children's Choir events, 1996; undated (Box-folder 67/5)
    - Programs for choir performances, 1970-2000 (Box-folder 67/6)
    - Annual reports for 1944 and 1945, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 67/7)
    - Rosters, 1972; circa 1975 (Box-folder 67/8)
    - Rosters, 1981-1982; undated (Box-folder 67/9)
    - Roster, 2004 (Box-folder 67/10)
    - Schedules, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 67/11)
    - Schedule charts, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 112/12)
    - Music schedules, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 67/12)
    - Tours in Europe, 1987; 1989 (Box-folder 67/13)
  - Programs for choral performances, 1895-1908 (Box-folder 67/14)
  - Poster for Maundy Thursday choral concert, circa 1985 (Box-folder 112/13)
  - Program for Christmas Eve music, 1986 (Box-folder 67/15)
  - Invitation card to Christmas music programs, 1953-1955; 1960; undated (Box-folder 67/16)
  - Program for concert held "for the benefit of the Near East relief", circa 1922 (Box-folder 67/17)
  - Programs for College Minstrels (Black and White) performances, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 67/18)
  - Concert program, circa 1923 (Box-folder 67/19)
  - Contracts, 1902-1903 (Box-folder 67/20)
  - Copenhagen Boys Choir concert, 1987 (Box-folder 67/21)
  - Script for "Council Choirs" broadcast on KPOJ, 1953 June 7 (Box-folder 67/22)
  - Program for dedication of memorial chimes in memory of Ruth Walker, undated (Box-folder 67/23)
  - Event schedules, 1971-1973; 1981 (Box-folder 67/24)
  - Program for "A Festival of Choirs" at Forest Grove United Church of Christ, 1984 April 29 (Box-folder 67/25)
  - Hawaii Youth Chorale concert, 1970 (Box-folder 67/26)
  - Hymn books, Subseries 2
    - "Bradbury's Fresh Laurels, for the Sabbath School", 1867 (Box-folder 67/27)
    - "The Song Evangel", 1873 (Box-folder 67/27)
    - "Popular Selections from Hymns New and Old," revised, 1891 (Box-folder 67/28)
    - "Living Hymns", 1923 (Box-folder 67/28)
    - Eunice W. Luckey's copy of "The Church Hymnal", 1890 (Box-folder 67/29)
  - Programs, flyers, etc. for Lenten recitals, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 67/30)
  - Marshall Islands Choir Concert, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 67/31)
    Also includes some attached documents.
  - Flyers and programs for musical performances at First Congregational Church, 1951; 1982-1995 (Box-folder 68/1)
  - Oregon Opera Ensemble performance at First Congregational Church, "Amahl and the Midnight Visitors", 1984 (Box-folder 68/2)
  - Organ, Subseries 3
    - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 68/3)
    - Memo of Agreement with Casavant Brothers Limited, 1950 September 22 (Box-folder 68/4)
      Company also known by French name Casavant Frères Limite.
    - Specifications for organ built by Casavant Frères Limite., 1951 (Box-folder 68/5)
      Company also known by English name Casavant Brothers Limited.
    - Correspondence, 1898-1899 (Box-folder 68/6)
    - Correspondence - Letter from Board of Trustees to Ladies Aid Society re organ motor, 1902 May 4 (Box-folder 68/7)
    - Correspondence from Edgar E. Coursen, 1903-1905 (Box-folder 68/8)
    - Correspondence - Letter to church clerk from Estey Organ Company, 1919 May 13 (Box-folder 68/9)
    - Correspondence and records, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 68/10)
    - Clippings re organist D. Deane Hutchison, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 68/11)
    - Documents and images relating to organ models, circa 1969 (Box-folder 68/12)
    - Notes about organ, chimes, and plaques, undated (Box-folder 68/13)
    - "Office copy" of documents re organ, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 68/14)
    - Rodgers Organ Model 22-B proposal and attached documents, 1967 October (Box-folder 68/15)
    - Proposals re Rodgers Organ Modell 110, 1969 October (Box-folder 68/16)
    - Program for organ dedicatory recital, 1951 December 7 (Box-folder 68/17)
    - Programs and ephemera for organ recitals, 1959-1961, 1983-1985, 1997-2005 (Box-folder 68/18)
    - Correspondence and records re organ restoration and upkeep, 1977-2004 (Box-folder 68/19)
    - Report on organ restoration, 1978 November 8 (Box-folder 68/20)
    - Specifications, 1962 (Box-folder Oversize 41)
    - Catalog for Van Zoeren organs, circa 1990 (Box-folder 68/21)
  - Piano, Subseries 4
    - Advertisements and catalogs for pianos, circa 1985 (Box-folder 68/22)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1992; undated (Box-folder 68/23)
    - Documents and ephemera re piano maintenance, 1981, undated (Box-folder 68/24)
    - Receipt for piano, 1990 December 15 (Box-folder 68/25)
  - Article about singer Michael Sanchez, 2005 (Box-folder 69/1)
  - Jerold Siena and Thomas Webb recital, 1991 April (Box-folder 69/2)
  - "Singing School" programs, 1905, 1921 (Box-folder 69/3)
  - Text of songs from 1920s era, undated (Box-folder 69/4)
  - Vocal recitals, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 69/5)
- Performing and visual arts, 1875-2016; Series M
  For administrative records of Artreach Commission and Music-Art-Drama Committee, see Series B: Groups.
  - Research files re Artreach Gallery (Box-folder 69/6)
  - Advertising for art exhibits, 1994-2011 (Box-folder 69/7)
  - Antique fashion show script, 1987 June 14 (Box-folder 69/8)
  - Antique fashion show script, undated (Box-folder 69/9)
  - Artreach Gallery show calendars, 2007-2016 (Box-folder 69/10)
  - Catalogs for art exhibits, 1875, 1888 (Box-folder 69/11)
  - Clippings re art exhibits, 1991, 2001-2005 (Box-folder 69/12)
  - Poster for free arts and crafts exhibit and advent concert, 1972 (Box-folder 112/14)
  - Program for "Bye-Byes, Birdie" at Summer Youth Festival, 1967 (Box-folder 69/13)
  - Script for "Cavalcade of Faith" by Evangeline Moke, 1951 (Box-folder 69/14)
    Play produced for church's centennial celebration.
  - Chancel Players - Flyers, programs, clippings, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 69/15)
  - Notes about Chancel Players, circa 1959 (Box-folder 69/16)
  - Program for "The Curious Savage", 1952 (Box-folder 69/17)